大家好，欢迎回到这个关于ASP.NET核心的视频系列。
Hi! Welcome back to this video series on ASP.NET Core.
我是jon galloway，我是jeff fritz。
I'm jon galloway and I'm jeff fritz.
我们将在这里讨论如何配置和处理多个环境，
so we're going to be talking here about configuring and working with multiple environments,
是的，我们已经讨论了生产和开发的配置
Yeah, we've-- we've kicked around this notion of production and development.
有趣的是，ASP.NET Core知道
It's funny ASP.NET Core actually knows
这些东西意味着什么，我们可以根据环境的运行来点亮不同的特性。
what these things mean and we can light up different features based on which environment were  operating.
你知道，这是其中一件事
You know that's-- that's one of those things where
当你回想起来的时候，我们总是在工作，就像你说的，有开发，有准备，有测试，有生产
when you think back about it we're always working with like you said there's development there's staging or test and there's production and that you know and
有了web框架很好，理解并了解它并与我一起工作
it's nice to have the web framework. understand that and know about that and work with me
当然
absolutely
我喜欢能够根据我的位置启用和禁用特性
I like being able to enable and disable features based on where I am
很好。
great.
让我们看一看。
let's take a look.
现在我在visual studio中。
so here I am in visual studio.
我要开始一个新项目
I'm going to start up a new project
我将选择构建一个新的aspnet核心应用程序。
and I'll choose to build a new aspnet core application.
我要把它放到我的开发文件夹里
I'm going to put it in my dev folder
我们把这个叫做环境。
and we will call this environments.
现在我要创建一个空的项目，
now I'm going to create an empty project,
因为我想把重点放在环境中不同的东西上，
because I want to focus on the different things that are available in the environments,
所以对我来说，它很快就被创造出来了
so it's created very quickly for me
当我打开program.cs
and I'll bring up my program.cs to start.
你可以看到我们从一开始就在做的就是创建我的默认构建器，使用我的启动类和构建
And you could see here all that we're doing right from the get-go is create my default builder ，use my startup class and built
这个startup 类在我们的第一个特性中配置了一些东西
Well, that startup class has just a few things configured in our first feature
这只在开发环境中启用，在第23到26行，它说如果环境是开发的，那么使用开发者异常页面
that's only enabled in development environment is right here on line 23 to 26, where it says if  the environment  is development ，then used a developer exception page
这对我调试的时候很好
and that's great for when I'm debugging
我希望能够看在我的应用程序中发生的确切的堆栈跟踪信息
and I want to be able to see the exact stack trace of it what happene
inside of my application.
当我想把它部署到我的生产空间时，
when I want to deploy this to my production space,
我宁愿使用一个更友好的错误处理程序
I'd rather use a more friendly error handler
这向我的访客展示了一些很好的信息
that shows some nice information  to my visitors
所以他们不会看到那个丑陋的堆栈跟踪。
so they don't get to see that ugly stack trace.
我告诉你，Jon，我在机场时最可怕的事
I tell you Jon， was the scariest thing when I at an airport
其中一个显示了所有航班起飞时间的显示屏
and one of those display screens showing the departure times for all the flights
显示的是旧的ASP.NET错误页面。
was showing the old ASP.NET error page.
哦！
Oh!
黄色的屏幕，旧的黄色屏幕哦，不，你不想在任何地方看到，尤其是在机场
The yellow screen of that, the old yellow screen oh,no you don't want to see that anywhere but especially not at the airport
因此，当您处于开发模式时，只显示开发人员异常页面是一件很好的事情。
So this is a good comfort thing to only show that developer exception page  when you're in development mode.
你知道，它能提高自信。
You know, it improves confidence.
因此，当我配置在普通应用程序上编写HTTP管道时，此配置方法就会运行
So this configure method runs when I configure my pipeline write my HTTP pipeline on a normal application
我有一个启动类
and I have this one startup class.
如果我导航到这个
and if I navigate to this
对，我要在这里抛出一个异常
right and I'm just going to throw an exception here
对吧？
right ?
这是一个错误。
that was an error.
我要运行这个。
and I'm going to run this.
当我从命令行运行这个时，
so when I run this now from my command line,
你会看到它会进行编译
you'll see it's going to do the compile
它会在开发环境中运行它监听这个网络地址和端口
and it's going to come back and say that it's running in the development environment in its listening on this web address  and port
好的
ok
我复制一下，我要用浏览器导航
let me copy that and I'm going to navigate there with my browser
写这个，就是那个错误信息
And write this is that-- that error message
我期望看到的是正确的，这是developer异常页面。
that I was expecting to see right,this is the developer exception page.
因为你在开发中你想说的
because you're in development you want to say that
所以我们可以修正它
so we can fix it. I can fix that right,
所以我的托管的是开发环境
so my hosting environment is development.
我得到了我的开发特性。
and I get my development feature enabled.
现在我可以改变它，我可以通过设置一个环境变量来打开一个不同的环境
Now I can change that and I can turn on a different environment by setting an environment variable
实际上visual studio在我配置应用程序时为我做了这个。
and infact visual studio did that for me  when I configured the application.
看看这个，我想去项目
check this out I want to go to project
属性，我将会看到调试在屏幕中间的位置
properties and I will look at Debug and right here in the middle of my screen
好了，
there we go,
它设置了一个环境变量当我从Visual Studio中启动时它说ASPNETCORE_ENVIRONMENT 是development
It sets up an environment variable when I launch  from within Visual Studio that says ASPNETCORE_ENVIRONMENT is development
所以无论什么时候我从visual studio开始。
so whenever I'm do bugging from visual studio.
我将会得到我在应用程序中配置的所有开发特性。
I'm going to get all those development features that I've configured inside of my application.
但我不是在visual studio中运行的
but I'm not running from within visual studio
我是从命令行运行的
I'm running from like command line.
Visual Studio为我点亮的下一个特性是在我的项目属性中，它生成了一个名为launch settings的文件。
The next feature that Visual Studio lit up for me is inside of my properties of the Project it generated a file called launch settings.
这是启动你的应用程序时使用的设置
and this is a bunch of settings that are used when you're launching your application to set the various things
这是我们在之前关于如何托管应用程序的视频中看到的
that actually we saw in a previous video video  around how to host your application.
你正监听的应用程序URL是什么
what is the application URL that you're listening on
甚至是一些环境变量。
and even some environment variables  right here.
因此，我们已经硬编码到这个配置中了，我们的开发模式配置
So, we've got hard-coded into this-- into this configuration  that we're in development mode,
因为我从命令行运行。
so because I ran from the command line.
它实际上在我的项目中运行了这组配置选项
it actually ran this set of configuration options into my project
所以我监听63439，它将我的环境设定为开发
so that I was listening on 63439 and it set my environment to development.
很好，对吧？
nice. okay ?
所以如果我不想要在这个文件里面的默认设置
so if I want that to not be set  by default  from  inside of  this file
我可以把它清除掉。
I can clear that out.
我把这个清除掉，如果我执行 dotnet run
I'll clear this and now if I  execute dotnet run
所以我执行了dotnet run，你看到它现在说托管环境是生产。
so I executed dotnet run and you see it's now saying the hosting environment is production.
所以，当我没有指定一个aspnetcoreenvironment时，
So, when I don't specify an ASPNETCORE_ENVIRONMENT,
它默认是在生产中运行，
it defaults to thinking it's running in production,
也就是说，所有我们说过的地方，如果这是开发环境这些额外的功能就会消失
which means all those places where we said ，if this is development putting these extra features  those things go away
它会表现得更像一个生产服务器
and it will behave more like a production server
我们将开始启用一些特性使它更安全，它使ASP.NET核心变硬
where we'll start turning on some features that  make it  a little bit more secure ，it hardens ASP.NET Core
让它感觉更多的生产准备就绪。
and makes it  feel  more production ready.
现在让我回到我的网站。
so now let me go back to my website.
当我刷新的时候。
and when I refreshed.
我没有得到我的错误，
I don't get my error. ah
没有任何东西可以通过这个错误返回。
there was nothing to return it through the error.
事实上，错误写在了日志里
and in fact that errors here inside my log.
但是它没有完成
but it didn't finish
为了防止这些信息泄露到我的应用程序之外，它没有返回任何东西，使屏幕保持空白
and to prevent any of that information from leaking  outside my application. it didn't return a thing ，  made that kept the screen blank
这里什么都没发生？
nothing happened here ?
很好，
great,
如果我有一个错误检查我可以将路径适当地路由到一些非常专门的错误页面
so if I did have  an error check and there I could  go route appropriately to some other  location some pretty professional looking error page
这与我的应用程序的其余部分完全一致。
absolute that fits in with the rest of my application.
这并不是像我在机场看到的那样，是一个关于末日的黄屏，也许是像一个拿着铲子的人的gif动画，
and isn't that a yellow screen of doom like I saw at the airport,maybe something like an animated gif of a man with a shovel,
就像一个建筑，1996年的网站叫做“约翰，我们想要你回来”，好的，
like a construction something 1996 website called "John we want you back".Alright,
这就是你如何配置你的网页来启用开发功能
so that's how you can Configure your web how you can light up that development feature
但是在这我们还可以做一些其他的事情。
but there's also some other things we can do here.
当我们构建我们的应用程序时，实际上是将不同的特性和配置引入不同的环境
as we build our application to actually pivot in bringing different features   and configure for different environments.
所以我们知道有一个简单的开发方法。
so we know there's an ease development method.
也有生产或准备阶段，以及这些测试，以确定环境是否被设置为生产或准备
there is also  is production  or is staging  and  those tests to see if the environment  is named  production  or staging.
我说得通。
I kind of make sense.
但是最后一个我想指出的是IsEnvironment
but this last one here that I want to point out IsEnvironment
这是一个有趣的问题，因为我可以为我想要测试的环境提供自己的字符串名称。
this is the interesting one because I can provide my own string name  for an environment that I want to test against.
开发，生产，分期，
So Development, Production, Staging,
这些可能不是您在组织中使用的术语。
those might not be the terms that you use with your organization.
你可以使用不同的名称，比如测试或集成
you might use a different name like test  or integration
对的
right
或者，无论您的组织使用什么环境名称。
or right whatever your organization uses  for your environment names.
您可以在这里创建并放置这些相同的测试，以验证您是否在该环境中运行，在您点亮不同的特性之前。
you can create and put those same tests in here to verify that you're operating in that environment.  before you light up  different features.
这是一件事，可以用if-statement来验证和配置东西，不管你想要什么，
now, that's one thing to pivot and put in if-statements to verify and Configure things.However you'd like,
但是你可以更进一步，我在这里有一个启动类
but you can actually go  even a step further where I have a Startup class here
我可以改变我的配置服务
I can actually change my configure services
它通过调用 Configure Services Development作为我的开发环境的配置服务。
that it triggers  a Configure Services that exists and is written for my development environment by calling it Configure Services Development.
因为我把我的环境的名字——放在膝盖上——在这个方法名的最后，
and because I've put the name of my environment-- at the knee-- at the end at the  end  of that method name,
它会在处于开发模式时执行此操作。
it will find this in execute this when it's in development mode.
现在，您可能想要有一个配置服务方法，以防它找不到与您所拥有的重写相匹配的环境名称。
now you're probably going to want to have a configure services method hanging around also   in case it can't find an environment name  that matches one of your overrides that you have here.
您可以在配置模式下使用相同的技巧，使用configure方法，我很抱歉
you can use that same trick with the configure mode . with the configure method ， I'm sorry
为了提供一个特定于该环境的特性。
in order to provide a feature that specific to being in that environment.
告诉你我复制这个，我要到下面这里添加另一个方法，
so tell you what let me just  copy this  and I'm going to go down here and add another method,
这次我把它叫ConfigureDevelopment
this time I'll call it ConfigureDevelopment
而不是将所有其他的东西都配置在管道中。
and instead of configuring all that other stuff in the pipeline.
我会说app.Run async context
I'm actually just going to sayapp.Run async context
对，
right,
我将会说await context.Response WriteAsync
and that I will say await context.Response WriteAsync
hello from development ；
hello from development  semicolon
很好，
good,
现在让我运行这个应用程序。
now let me run that application.
所以现在它认为我的产品都更新了，我仍然能得到我的空白页。
so now it thinks I'm in production all refreshed and I still get my blank page.
现在我们取消这个
so now let's cancel this
让我将我的ASPNETCORE ENVIRONMEN设置为开发
let me set my ASPNETCORE ENVIRONMENT core environment  to development
重新运行应用程序，现在它认为我在开发环境中。
and rerun the application,  and now it thinks  I'm in the development environment.
所以我要回去
so I'll go back
刷新
refresh
它说 hello from development.
and it says hello from development.
所以我可以嵌入不同的配置方法来配置我的应用程序
so I can  embed  different  configuration methods  that point to in configure my application
这取决于我的意思
differently depending on which environment I mean
所以这些是您可以选择用作构建应用程序的选项。
so those are options that you can choose to use as your building out your application.
最后一个技巧，我想确保你说
one last trick with that that I want to make sure you say
回到我的代码中。
I'm going to go back into my code here.
而且，除了有一个配置的开发方法之外
and, besides having a configured development method
对的
right
我把它删掉
I'll get rid of that
我也可以在这里有一个不同的启动类，
I can actually have a different startup class sitting here as well,
如果我创建了public class  startupdevelopment
so check this out if I create public class  startupdevelopment
对。
right.
我需要一个配置服务和一个配置方法，所以我将从复制这些开始。
I need a configure services and a configure method in there so I will just start off by copying these.
在这，我同样应用 app.Run async context await context.Response Write 这次我们说 Hello from Startup Development.
and in this one I will do the exact same app.Run async context await context.Response Write and this time we will say Hello from Startup Development.
好的。
all right.
扫一下。它会完成的。
Sem it. it will finish it.
现在为了让我能够使用这个Startup类，我让它根据环境名称检测使用我想要的Startup类，
Now in order for me to be able to use this Startup class and I have it detecting use the Startup class that I want based on the environment name,
我需要做一点改变
I need to make a slight change here
从它开始的地方指定了一种特定的类。
from where it says you start up in specifies a specific sort of class.
我需要告诉它代替要搜索此启动类的程序集并运行相应的程序集。
I need to tell it instead what assembly  to go search for this startup class in   and run the appropriate one.
我的程序集称为环境。
so my assemblies called environments.
所以我把它叫做环境，
so I will just call it  environments,
它会找到合适的启动类来运行。
and it will go find the appropriate startup class for me to run.
所以我要取消这个
so I will cancel this
再次运行
I'll dot net run again
所以它认为我在开发环境中运行。
so it thinks I'm running in the development environment.
我从这里刷新一下
I'll refresh from over here
它说 hello from startup development.
and it says hello from startup development.
我们已经写了一些代码
so we've written a little bit of code
所以我们写了一些代码，能够解释，
so we written a little bit of code that is able to interpret,
我们所处的环境对于不同的环境需要使用不同的特性并根据需要触发不同的配置
what environment we are on use different features around the Startup class as needed for those different environments and trigger different configurations as needed
好的
ok
对于在不同环境中有不同需求的人来说，这是一个很好的配置选项。
this is a great configuration option for folks who have different needs  in different environments.
也许你在一个受监管的环境中，你的生产空间是由HIPAA规则管理的。
maybe you're in a regulated environment in your production space is is governed by HIPAA rules.
有些是你想要在开发中使用的，而这些东西是永远无法投入生产的。
and there are certain things that you only want to light up in development  that  can never get into production.
你可以写一个启动生产类，它排除了所有没有人可以改变的开发项
you can do things around writing a startup production class that excludes  all of those development things that  nobody can change,
你可以确保每次你进入生产阶段的时候都是如此
and you can make sure is the one that runs  every time when you get into production
我可以看到所有类型的用户，比如你展示了开发异常页面，我可能想要一些样本数据
I can see all kinds of users， like you showed the development exception page ，I may want to have some sample data
也许当我在开发模式下运行时我想要有大量的数据
maybe when I'm running in development mode I want to have a ton of data that's going to
因为我都在一个本地的网络上，我希望我的开发人员能感受到在耶鲁加载一个大页面的痛苦，
cause I'm all on a local network and I want my developers to feel the pain of loading a large page at yale than ever it is,
或者我想在我的页面上显示分析信息，页面运行和加载速度很快
and or I may want to show it was pretty common to show profiling information on my page in development  Right， what is my page running and loading quickly
这样的分析，然后当我在生产的时候，我可能想要把所有的东西都记录下来，
that kind of profiling and then when I'm in production I may want to dial all that down，
所以，我喜欢你展示的所有这些不同的方法，然后我如何使用这些自定义的启动类来形成他
So, all I love that you showed all those different ways ,and then how I can use those custom Startup classes to kind of formalize that.
请说
yep
最后一件事，visual studio浏览器链接工具在默认情况下使用相同的机制来检查它的开发模式
last thing. the  visual studio browser link tool is enabled by default using that same mechanism where it checks if its development mode
在默认的应用程序模板中，
in the default application templates as well,
你知道这是另一件你指出的事情，他们的是我可以设定断点，我可以一步一步地说，就像在开发或者别的什么。
you know  that's one other thing you pointed out ,theirs  is that I can set break points and I can actually step through and say like is in development or whatever.
这是一个很好的事情，那就是代码实际上是代码，所以我可以调试它，我知道你可以在我开发的时候改变它们或者使用它。
that's a neat thing there is that code is actually， it's code so I can debug it,I can you know change their or work with it as I'm developing.
非常感谢您观看我们关于您可能正在开发的不同环境的视频。
so thanks  so much for joining us for this video about different environments that you may be working on.
我们还有一些关于ASP.NET core的视频
We have a couple more videos  about ASP.NET core for you
我希望你能加入我们。
I hope you come back and join us.